[ MAN BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Ahh !
[ MAN SCREAMS ]
MAN : Tina .
Tina .
[ MAN CHUCKLING ]
[ CLATTERING ]
[ BLEATS ]
[ MAN LAUGHING ]
[ CLANKING ]
[ METAL SQuEAKS ]
[ MAN LAUGHING ]
WOMAN : Tina . Tina .
[ GASPS ]
[ MAN YELLS ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ MAN BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SHEEP BLEATING AND BABY CRYING ]
[ MAN YELLS ]
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
You okay , Tina ?
Just a dream , Ma .
Some dream , judging from that .
- You coming back to the sack or what ? - Hold your horses .
Tina , honey , you gotta cut your fingernails
or you gotta stop that kind of dreaming .
One or the other .
GIRLS [ CHANTING ] : One , two Freddy 's coming for you
Three , four Better lock your door
Five , six Grab your crucifix
Seven , eight Gonna stay up late
Nine , 10 Never sleep again
TINA : It was so scary .
When I woke up , it seemed like he was still in the room .
NANCY : Sounds like a real boogeyman . " One , two , Freddy 's coming for you . "
That 's what it reminded me of : that old jump-rope song .
The worst nightmare I ever had . You wouldn 't believe it .
Matter of fact , I had a bad dream last night myself .
I had a hard-on this morning when I woke up , Tina .
- Had your name written all over it . - There 's four letters in my name , Rod .
How could there be room on your joint for four letters ?
[ ALL laughing ]
Hey , up yours with a twirling lawn mower .
Nyah ! Rod says the sweetest things .
- Oh , he 's nuts about you . - Yeah , nuts .
Anyway , I couldn 't go back to sleep last night .
- So , what did you dream ? - Forget it , Tina .
The point is that everyone has a bad dream once in a while .
It 's no biggie .
Just tell yourself that 's all it is while you 're having it .
Once you do that , you wake right up . At least it works for me .
Hey ! Did you have a nightmare too ?
Maybe we 're gonna have a big earthquake . They say things get really weird just before .
TINA : I 'm so glad you guys could come over tonight .
When Mom said she was taking off for two days , I almost died .
NANCY : No problem , Tina . Nancy and Glen to the rescue .
[ ROCK music PLAYING ON RADIO ]
Can 't believe his mother 's letting him spend the night .
Right , well , she 's not , exactly .
I got this cousin who lives near the airport . It 's okay for me to stay with him .
And I got this sound-effects tape from Rod , and ...
Hello , Mom ?
Yeah . Out here at Barry 's .
[ AIRPLANE ENGINE ROARING ON TAPE ]
Huh ? Yeah , noisy as usual . Glad we don 't live here , huh ?
Yeah , Aunt Eunice says hello .
Right , right , I 'll call you in the morning . Yeah . Yeah , sure ...
[ CAR ENGINE ACCELERATING ON TAPE ]
Just some kids drag-racing outside , I think , Mom .
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
[ CAR CRASHES ON TAPE ]
Listen , Ma . I gotta go . I think there 's been an accident out front .
[ WOMAN SCREAMING ON TAPE ]
Right .
[ EXPLOSIONS AND GUNFIRE ON TAPE ]
All right , I 'll call the police .
Right , I 'll call the police .
uh ...
No . Just some neighbors having a fight , I guess .
I 'll call you in the morning .
[ TINA NANCY laughing ]
It worked like a charm .
Smooth .
Jesus .
See ? I told you you 'd be feeling better .
All day long , I 've been seeing that guy 's weird face
and hearing those fingernails .
Fingernails ?
That 's amazing , you saying that .
That made me remember the dream I had last night .
What did you dream ?
I dreamed about a guy in a dirty red and green sweater .
Well , what about the fingernails ?
Oh , he scraped his fingernails along things .
Actually , they were more like finger-knives or something .
Something he made himself , but they made a horrible sound .
It was like :
[ IMITATES SCRAPING ]
Nancy , you dreamed about the same creep I did .
That 's impossible .
[ SQuEAKING ]
What ?
Nothing .
- There 's something out there , isn 't there ? - I didn 't hear anything .
Well , I heard something .
[ DOG BARKING ]
[ SQuEAKING ]
I 'm gonna punch out your ugly lights , whoever you are .
Kitty , kitty .
[ RUSTLING ]
Chow , chow , chow .
It 's Rod Lane bringing Lantz down just three yards from the goal line !
What a brilliant tackle , and the fans go wild .
- What the hell are you doing here ? - Came to make up . No big deal .
- Your mom home ? - Course .
- Oh , what 's that ? - Intense , huh ?
[ IMITATES SCRAPING ]
So , what 's going on here , an orgy or something ?
Maybe a funeral , dickhead .
It 's just a sleepover date , Rod .
Tina and me . Glen was just leaving .
- You see his face ? - " You see his face ? "
Your mom ain 't home , is she ?
Me and Tina got stuff to discuss .
Rod .
We got her mother 's bed . You guys got the rest .
I think we should get out of here .
TINA : Hey , you guys are gonna hang around , right ?
I mean , don 't leave me alone with this lunatic .
Please , Nancy ?
[ TINA GIGGLING ]
Glen , not now .
We 're here for Tina now , not ourselves .
Why is she so bothered by a stupid nightmare , anyway ?
Because he was scary , that 's why .
ROD : Yeah .
[ ROD TINA MOANING ]
TINA : Oh , Rod !
ROD : Yeah . Yeah , Tina !
TINA : Oh , God ! Oh , God !
Oh , God !
Oh , God ! Oh , Rod !
Morality sucks .
[ ROD GRuNTS ]
I knew there was something about you I liked .
- You feel better now , right ? - Jungle man fix Jane .
No more fights ?
No more fights .
Good .
No more nightmares for either one of us , then .
When did you have a nightmare ?
Guys can have nightmares too , you know .
You ain 't got a corner on the market or something .
[ WIND HOWLING ]
[ PEBBLE CLATTERS ]
Rod ?
[ ROD SNORES ]
[ PEBBLE CLATTERS ]
MAN : Tina .
Tina .
Who do you think you are ?
Whoever you are .
Somebody there ?
MAN : Tina .
Tina .
Who the hell is that ?
[ GASPS ]
Tina .
Shit .
[ LAUGHING ]
Please , God ...
This
is God .
[ TINA SCREAMS ]
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
TINA : No ! No ! No !
FREDDY : Yes !
Tina !
Watch this .
Nancy ! Open the door !
Nancy !
[ CACKLING ]
[ TINA SCREAMS ]
[ TINA SCREAMING ]
TINA : Rod , help me ! Oh , God !
No ! No !
Help me , Rod !
Help me ! Rod ! Rod !
- Help me ! - Tina !
[ TINA GRUNTING ]
ROD : Tina !
Tina ! Tina !
Tina !
- Tina ! - Rod ! Rod !
- Tina ? Tina ? ROD : Who did this ? I 'll kill you .
- Who did this ? - Aaagh ! Oh , God , you scared me !
[ ROD GRuNTING ]
What have you got ?
Her name was Tina Gray . It 's her home .
Father abandoned 10 years ago , mother 's in Vegas with her boyfriend .
- We 're trying to reach her . - What 's the coroner got ?
Something like a razor was the weapon , but nothing was found at the scene .
It looks like the victim 's boyfriend .
GARCIA : Lieutenant . - Where is she ?
- I put her in your office . - His name 's Rod Lane . He 's a musician type .
- Arrests for drugs , brawling . - Terrific . What the hell was she doing there ?
She lived there .
I don 't mean her .
I mean you .
What was she doing there ?
Hello to you too , Donald .
Marge . Okay .
How you doing , baby ?
I 'm okay , Dad .
Look , I don 't wanna get into this now
God knows you need time , but I sure would like to know
what the hell you were doing shacking up with three kids in the middle of the night
especially a lunatic delinquent like Lane .
Rod is not a lunatic , Dad .
You have a sane explanation for what he did ?
Apparently , he was crazy jealous .
- Nancy said they 'd had a fight . - It wasn 't that serious .
Maybe you don 't think murder is serious .
How can you say I don 't take her death seriously ?
Look , all I meant
was that their fights weren 't that serious .
You know , Tina
she dreamed this was gonna happen .
What ?
She had a nightmare that someone was trying to kill her .
That 's why we were there , Mom . She just didn 't wanna sleep alone .
[ SOBBING ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : Police say the victim , 15-year-old Christina Gray
had quarreled earlier with her boyfriend , Rod Lane .
Lane is now the subject of a citywide manhunt .
The murder weapon , a straight razor or similar sharp object , has not yet ...
Where do you think you 're going ?
School .
You were tossing and turning all night last night .
You have no business going to school today .
I 've gotta go to school , Mother . Otherwise I 'll sit up there and go crazy .
Did you sleep ?
I 'll sleep in study hall .
I 'd rather keep busy , you know ?
- Right home after ? - Right home after .
Okay .
- See you . - See you .
[ muffled GRuNTING ]
I 'm not gonna hurt you . I 'm not gonna hurt you .
- They 're gonna kill me for sure . - Nobody 's gonna kill you .
Did you do it ?
- I never touched her . - You were screaming like crazy .
There was somebody else there .
The door was locked from your side .
Don 't look at me like I 'm some fucking fruitcake or something !
- I 'm warning you . - Just move away from her , son .
Real easy , like your ass depended on it .
Hold it !
- No ! - Jesus Christ .
[ SIRENS APPROACHING ]
COP 1 : Hold it right there .
COP 2 : Watch it . Hold them . - All right . I 'm cool , I 'm cool .
COP 1 : Okay , I got him . COP 3 : On the ground , now .
COP 1 : Come on . Get down . - Lieutenant , look at this . A switchblade .
ROD : I didn 't do it ! I didn 't kill her , Nancy !
NANCY : Daddy ?
You used me .
What the hell were you doing going to school today for anyway ?
Nancy .
Nancy !
- Nancy ! ROD : Come on , let go of my arm .
What is seen is not always what is real .
According to Shakespeare , there was something operating in nature
perhaps inside human nature itself , that was rotten .
A canker , as he put it .
Now , of course , Hamlet 's response to this
and to his mother 's lies , was to continually probe and dig .
Just like the gravediggers
always trying to get beneath the surface .
The same is true in a different way in Julius Caesar . John , go ahead , please .
uh ...
In the most high and palmy state of Rome , a little ere the mightiest Julius fell .
The graves stood tenantless , and the sheeted dead
did squeak and gibber in the Roman streets :
As stars with trains of fire and dews of blood
disasters in the sun , and the moist star
upon whose influence Neptune 's empire stands ...
TINA : Nancy .
Nancy .
O God ! I could be bounded in a nutshell
and count myself a king of infinite space
were it not that I have bad dreams .
Tina ?
[ SCREAMING ]
- Where 's your pass ? - Screw your pass .
FREDDY : Hey , Nancy .
[ IN FREDDY 'S VOICE ] No running in the hallway .
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
Tina ?
[ METAL CLANGS ]
[ FREDDY BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Tina ?
Who are you ?
[ CACKLING ]
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
Gonna get you .
- It 's only a dream ! - Come to Freddy .
Goddamn you !
[ NANCY SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
NANCY : No ! No !
Okay ! Okay , okay ! Thompson !
I 'll call your mother .
Everything is all right now .
- Come on . Sit down . - No .
I 'm okay . I 'm fine .
TEACHER : You sure ? - Yeah . I 'll go straight home .
You 'll need a hall pass .
uh ...
Back to work .
[ SIGHS ]
[ SOBBING ]
God !
- And then what happened ? - I told you .
It was dark , but I 'm sure there was somebody in there
under the covers with her .
How could somebody be under the covers with you without you knowing about it ?
How the fuck do I know ?
I don 't expect you to believe me anyway .
What did he look like ?
Did you get a look at him ?
No .
Well , then how do you know that somebody else was there ?
Because somebody cut her while I watched .
- And you didn 't get a look at him ? - I couldn 't even see the fucker .
You could just see
cuts happening
all at once .
What do you mean all at once ?
I mean , it was as if there were four razors
cutting her at the same time
but invisible ones .
You know , I probably could have saved her
if I 'd have moved sooner
but I thought it was just another nightmare
like the one I had the night before .
There was this ... There was this guy .
He had knives for fingers .
Hey , you think I did it ?
No .
[ CHANTING ] One , two Freddy 's coming for you
Three , four Better lock your door
Five , six Grab your crucifix
Seven , eight Gonna stay up late
Nine , 10 Never sleep again
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
MARGE : Nancy ? - What , Mother ?
Don 't fall asleep in there .
- You could drown , you know . - Oh , for Pete 's sakes .
It happens all the time .
I 've heated up some warm milk for you .
Warm milk ? Gross .
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
Help !
Nancy !
[ GASPING ]
- Hold on , baby ! - Mom !
I 'm okay .
- You 're okay ? - I 'm okay .
But I heard you screaming . You were calling me .
I just slipped getting out of the tub , Mom .
I told you hundreds of people a year get killed like that , honey .
I know , but I 'm okay , Mother . I 'm sorry for scaring you .
It 's okay .
I 'll turn down your bed , okay ?
All right . I 'll get my pajamas on .
Okay .
MAN [ ON TV ] : all-consuming act of bodily dismemberment .
WOMAN : No ! No !
[ WOMAN SCREAMING ON TV ]
GLEN : Hi . - God !
I 'm sorry . Your light was on . I thought I 'd see how you were .
Sometimes I wish you didn 't live right across the street .
Will you shut up and let me in ? Ever stand on a trellis in your bare feet ?
NANCY : Get inside before somebody sees you .
GLEN : Ow ! NANCY : Shh !
GLEN : I hit my head .
NANCY : Gotta be quiet . Mom 's not even asleep yet .
If you don 't mind .
I heard you freaked out in English class today .
- Yeah , I guess I did . - You haven 't slept yet , have you ?
- Not really . - What did you do to your arm ?
I burned it in English class .
Oh , God . I look 20 years old .
Did you have any weird dreams last night ?
Slept like a rock .
Do you believe that people can dream about what 's going to happen ?
- No . - Do you believe in the boogeyman ?
No .
Rod killed Tina , and you know that .
I 've got a crazy favor to ask you .
- uh-oh . - It 's nothing hard or anything .
I 'm gonna go and look for somebody
and I want you to stand like a sort of a guard , okay ?
[ WAILS ]
- Okay ? - Okay .
Now , you can 't mess up . A lot might depend on this .
I won 't screw up .
Okay , turn off the light .
- Okay , here 's what we 're gonna do . - It 's dark in here .
And it 's not what you 're thinking .
Glen ?
Are you still watching ?
- Yeah , so ? - I 'm just checking .
[ DOG BARKING NEARBY ]
Glen !
Glen ?
Rod ! Watch out ! Rod ! Watch out !
Glen !
- Glen ! TINA : Nancy .
Nancy .
NANCY : Glen !
Wake up !
Are you there ?
MAN 'S VOICE : I 'm here .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ FREDDY GROWLING ]
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
TINA : Nancy , help me , please .
- Save me from ... - Freddy .
Glen !
This is just a dream . This isn 't real . This is just a dream . He isn 't real . He isn 't ...
[ FREDDY YELLS ]
[ NANCY SCREAMING ]
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
Glen !
No !
Glen , no !
[ ALARM CLOCK RINGING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ RINGING STOPS ]
Glen , you bastard .
What did I do ?
I just asked you to do one thing , just stay awake and watch me
just wake me up if it looked like I was having a bad dream
and what did you do ? You shithead . You fell asleep .
MARGE : Nancy ? GLEN : Oh , shit .
- Hurry . GLEN : Ow .
NANCY : Shh .
Shut up and stay there . Don 't go away .
Are you okay ?
Yeah . It was just a little dream . I 'm going right back to sleep .
Okay . Call me if you need anything , okay ?
Okay .
Glen .
- You mind telling me what 's going on ? - Oh , just come on .
Yeah .
Garcia , I 've gotta see Rod Lane again .
You know , I took the night shift so I could get some peace and quiet .
Look , it 's urgent !
[ SNORING ]
[ FREDDY CHUCKLING ]
We have reason to believe there might be something strange going on here .
Got no argument with that .
What are you doing here ?
There 's an unsolved murder , and I don 't like unsolved murders .
Especially ones that my daughter 's mixed up in .
What are you doing here ?
- At this hour , you should be home in bed . - I just wanna see if he 's okay .
Nancy , take my word for it . The guy 's sleeping like a baby .
He 's not going anywhere .
Just go down and look at him .
Please , Daddy .
All right . Garcia , give me the keys .
All right .
Where the hell did I put the keys ?
ROD : Hey , hey !
[ SCREAMING ]
Help ! Help ! Help !
Jesus !
Rod !
Hurry . Cut him down .
GARCIA : Grab his legs . THOMPSON : I got him .
NANCY : God !
Goddamn crazy kid .
THOMPSON : Grab his back , would you ? - Got it .
Lower him .
Ashes to ashes , dust to dust .
May God be with this young man 's soul .
His life and his death attest to the scriptures ' warning
that he who lives by the sword shall die by the sword .
But let us recall also our Lord 's admonition
that we judge not , lest we be judged .
And may Rod Lane rest in peace .
MARGE : Time to go , honey .
Hop in .
The killer 's still loose , you know .
You 're saying somebody else killed Tina . Who ?
I don 't know who he is
but he 's burned , and he wears a weird hat
and a red and green sweater , really dirty
and he uses these knives , like giant fingernails .
Better keep her home for a few days , until she gets over the shock of this .
I 've got something better . I 'm going to get her some help .
I don 't see why you couldn 't just give me a pill to keep me from dreaming .
Everyone 's got to dream , young lady . If you don 't dream , you go .
Okay , all set ?
- No . - Please , Nancy , trust us .
It 's not you I don 't trust . It 's just ...
Okay .
Let 's do it .
- Thank you , nurse . NURSE : Mm-hm .
KING : How long has this been going on ? - Since the murders .
She was fine before that .
Now she thinks her dreams are real .
Well , there 's no sign of pathology in her EEG .
I 'd guess that what we have is just a normal girl
who happens to have gone through two days of hell .
Okay .
She 's asleep now .
Thank God .
What the hell are dreams anyway ?
Mysteries . Incredible body hocus-pocus .
The truth is we still don 't know what they are or where they come from .
Okay . She 's going into deep sleep now .
Heart rate is a little high . It 's just due to anxiety .
Otherwise she 's nicely relaxed .
All signs are normal . She could dream at any time now .
Beta waves are slowing .
She 's into REMs now .
She 's definitely dreaming now .
It 's a good one too . Typical dream parameter .
A nightmare now would be plus or minus five or six .
She 's about three .
[ sound OF METAL SQuEAKING AND WATER DRIPPING ]
[ GRuNTING ]
- Doctor , what 's she doing now ? - I 'm not ...
Is she asleep or awake ?
Something 's wrong . It never gets this high .
- What 's she doing ? - I don 't know .
MARGE : Is she dreaming ?
[ CHOKING ]
[ NANCY SCREAMING ]
NURSE : Listen ... - Nancy ! Nancy , it 's Mom , it 's Mom .
Nancy . It 's Mom .
What ? Her hair .
- Excuse me . NURSE : This 'll help you sleep .
NANCY : No !
Oh , my God , her arm ! Get something .
What happened , baby ? What happened ?
It 's okay , it 's okay .
I brought something out from my dream .
Where did you get that ?
I grabbed it off his head .
MARGE : Donald , she said she grabbed it off his head in her dream .
No , I 'm not crazy .
I 'm holding the damn thing right here in my hand .
I don 't know where she really found it . I gotta go .
You didn 't sleep at all last night , did you ?
- The doctor says you have to sleep , or ... - I 'll go even crazier ?
I don 't think you 're crazy , and stop drinking that damn coffee .
So did you ask Daddy to have the hat examined ?
I threw that filthy thing away .
I don 't know where you found it or what you 're trying to prove ...
What I learned in the dream clinic , that 's what I 'm trying to prove , Mother .
Rod didn 't kill Tina , and he didn 't hang himself .
It 's this guy .
He 's after us in our dreams .
That 's just not reality , Nancy .
It 's real , Mama .
Feel it .
- Give me that damn thing . - It even has his name written in it .
Fred Krueger , Mom .
Fred Krueger .
Do you know who that is , Mother ? Because if you do , you better tell me
because he 's after me now .
Nancy , trust your mother for once , please .
You 'll feel better when you get some sleep .
Feel better ?
You call this feeling better ?
Or maybe I should grab that bottle and veg out with you .
Avoid everything happening to me by just getting good and loaded .
Fred Krueger can 't come after you , Nancy .
He 's dead . Believe me . I know .
You knew about him all this time
and you 've been acting like it was something I made up ?
Nancy , you 're sick .
There 's something wrong with you . You 're imagining things .
You 'll feel better when you sleep . It 's just as simple as that .
Screw sleep !
Nancy , it 's just a nightmare .
That 's enough .
GLEN : Whenever I get nervous , I eat .
NANCY : And if you can 't do that , you sleep .
GLEN : I used to .
Not anymore .
Did you ever read about the Balinese way of dreaming ?
NANCY : No .
They got this whole system they call dream skills .
So if you have a nightmare , for instance , like falling , right ?
- Right . - Well
instead of screaming and getting all nuts
you say , " Okay , I 'm gonna make up my mind
that I fall into a magic world . "
Make it something special like a poem or a song .
They get their art and literature from dreams .
Just wake up and write it down . Dream skills .
Well , what if they meet a monster in their dreams ? Then what ?
They turn their back on it . Take away its energy and it disappears .
But what happens if they don 't do that ?
Well , I guess those people don 't wake up to tell what happens .
Great .
" Booby Traps and improvised Anti-personnel Devices " ?
Well , what are you reading that for ?
I 'm into survival .
- See you . GLEN : You 're starting to scare me .
Oh , gross .
Mother !
What 's with the bars ?
- Security . - Security ?
- Security from what ? - Not from what , from whom .
Come down to the cellar with me and I 'll tell you .
You wanna know who Fred Krueger was ?
He was a filthy child murderer who killed at least 20 kids in the neighborhood .
Kids we all knew .
Oh , Mom .
It drove us crazy when we didn 't know who it was
but it was even worse after they caught him .
Did they put him away ?
The lawyers got fat and the judge got famous
but somebody forgot to sign the search warrant in the right place
and Krueger was free , just like that .
What did you do , Mother ?
A bunch of us parents tracked him down after they let him out .
We found him in an old abandoned boiler room where he used to take his kids .
Go on .
We took gasoline
we poured it all around the place and made a trail of it out the door
then lit the whole thing up and watched it burn .
But he can 't get you now .
He 's dead , honey , because Mommy killed him .
I even took his knives .
So it 's okay now .
You can sleep .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- Hello . NANCY : Hi .
- Oh , hi , how you doing ? - Fine .
Stand by your window so I can see you . You sound a million miles away .
That 's much better .
GLEN : I see your mom went ape at the security store today .
You look like the Prisoner of Zenda .
- How long 's it been since you slept ? - It 's coming up on the seventh day .
It 's okay . I checked Guinness . The record 's 11 .
Listen , Glen . I know who he is .
- Who ? - The killer .
- You do ? - Yes .
And if he gets me , I 'm pretty sure you 're next .
Me ? Why would anybody wanna kill me ?
Don 't ask . Just give me some help nailing the guy
when I bring him out .
- Bring him out of what ? - My dream .
- How do you plan to do that ? - Just like I did the hat .
Have a hold of the sucker when you wake me up .
What ... ? Wait a minute .
You can 't bring somebody out of a dream .
If I can 't , then you can all relax , because it 's just a case of me being nuts .
Yeah , well , I can save you the trouble . You 're nutty as a fruitcake .
- I love you anyway . - Good .
Then you won 't mind cold-cocking this guy when I bring him out .
- What ? - You heard me .
I grab the guy in my dream . You see me struggling , so you wake me up .
We both come out , you whack the fucker , and we got him .
Are you crazy ? Hit him with what ?
You 're the jock . You have a baseball bat or something .
Just meet me at my porch at midnight .
- Oh , and meanwhile ... - Meanwhile ?
Whatever you do , don 't fall asleep .
Midnight ?
Oh , man .
Midnight .
Baseball bats and boogeymen .
Beautiful .
Glen . Honey ?
Glen .
Glen . Glen .
How can you listen to television and hear your records at the same time ?
Oh , I wasn 't listening to the tube , Ma . Just watching .
Miss Nude America is gonna be on tonight .
- How can you hear what she 's going to say ? - Who cares what she says ?
Don 't be such a smart guy .
I want you to go to bed . It 's almost midnight .
Goodness knows we 've all had a lot to deal with these last few days .
- I will , Mom . You guys turning in ? - Pretty soon . Now get to bed .
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
It 's over now , baby . The nightmare 's over .
Please .
Okay .
You shouldn 't stare .
You know what I think ?
I think that kid is some kind of lunatic or something .
Oh , you shouldn 't talk that way about that poor child .
You mean those bars ?
Marge is just being cautious , what with her being all alone
and Nancy acting so nervous lately .
I don 't care what you say .
I don 't want that kid hanging around with our son anymore .
[ RINGING ]
Glen , answer the phone .
Hello .
Just a minute . It 's her . She wants to talk to Glen .
About what ?
What 's this about , Nancy ?
Just a minute .
She says it 's private , very private and very important .
Give me that . Glen 's asleep . You 'll have to talk to him tomorrow .
You 've just gotta be firm with these kids , that 's all . Let 's go .
As a matter of fact ...
[ busy SIGNAL ]
Damn .
Glen . Don 't fall asleep .
[ PHONE RINGS ]
Glen ?
[ METAL SQuEAKING ]
No !
Oh , brilliant .
What if Glen tries to call ?
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- Hello . FREDDY : I 'm your boyfriend now , Nancy .
[ SCREAMING ]
My boyfriend .
- Mom ! - Locked , locked , locked , locked .
I locked it all up . I had to .
Nancy , you are going to get some sleep tonight if it kills me .
Give me the key , Mother .
I can 't . I don 't even have it on me . See ?
Damn it !
[ " STAR-SPANGLED BANNER " PLAYING ON HEADPHONES ]
[ SNORING ]
ANNOuNCER [ ON RADIO ] : It is now 12 midnight
and this is Station KRGR leaving the air .
No ! No ! No ! Ma !
[ GLEN SCREAMING ]
Glen ! Glen !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
MEDIC : Come on , Frankie . Give me a hand . Come on .
COP : You won 't need a stretcher up there . You 'll need a mop .
MEDIC : Let 's go . Let 's go .
MAN : Hey !
THOMPSON : Don 't tell me it 's another one .
Lieutenant , I 'm sorry to wake you
but I 've never seen anything like this before
and this is your neighborhood , so I thought I 'd better call right away .
The coroner 's upstairs now , but I don 't think he 's gonna ...
Would have woke me up .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
Oh , my God .
PARKER : Hello ? Huh ?
Yeah , I 'll get him right away .
Lieutenant , it 's your daughter .
- Nancy . - Hi , Daddy .
- I know what happened . - I haven 't been upstairs yet .
Yeah , but you know he 's dead , right ?
Yeah . Apparently he 's dead .
Listen , Daddy . I 've got a proposition for you .
- Listen very carefully , please . - Nancy .
I 'm gonna go and get the guy who did it
and I want you to be there to arrest him when I bring him out , okay ?
Just tell me who did it . I 'll go get him , baby .
Fred Krueger did it , Daddy , and only I can get him .
It 's my nightmare he comes to .
Just come here and break the door down in exactly 20 minutes .
- Can you do that ? - Yeah , sure .
That 'll be exactly half past midnight .
Time ... Time enough for me to fall asleep and find him .
Honey , look , you just do that . Get yourself some sleep .
- That 's what I 've been telling you . - But you 'll be here ?
- They 're waiting for you upstairs . - Yeah . Sure , I 'll be there , sweetheart .
Now , look , you just get yourself some rest , please . Deal ?
- Deal . - I love you , sweetheart .
Look , go outside and watch my daughter 's house .
- lf you see anything funny , call me . - Anything funny ? Like what ?
I don 't know . One thing for sure , I don 't want her coming over here .
She 's too far gone to be able to handle this .
- What the hell did that , lieutenant ? - I don 't know .
- What 's the coroner got to say ? - He 's in the john puking since he saw it .
I guess I should have told you about him then .
Let 's just get some sleep , Mom . It 's gonna be okay .
I was just trying to protect you .
I didn 't see how much you needed to know .
You face things . That 's your nature .
That 's your gift
but sometime you have to turn away too .
I love you .
I love you too , baby .
Night .
Okay , Krueger .
We play in your court .
[ SIREN WAILING ]
And now I lay me down to sleep . I pray the Lord my soul to keep
and if I die before I wake , I pray the Lord my soul to take .
automated VOICE : Countdown mode . Ten minutes and counting .
NANCY : What if they meet a monster in their dreams ? Then what ?
GLEN : They turn their back on it . Take away its energy and it disappears .
NANCY : But what happens if they don 't do that ?
GLEN : Well , then I guess those people don 't wake up to tell what happens .
[ WATER TRICKLING ]
[ METAL SQuEAKING ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
TINA : Nancy .
[ FREDDY CHUCKLING ]
TINA : You dreamed about the same creep I did .
FREDDY : Gonna get you .
[ FREDDY LAUGHING ]
GLEN : No ! No ! No !
[ FREDDY GROWLS ]
[ FREDDY BREATHING HEAVILY ]
TINA : Nancy .
Krueger !
I 'm here !
[ METAL SQuEAKS ]
Come out and show yourself , you bastard !
[ WATCH BEEPS ]
Shit .
[ SCREAMING ]
Come on , Krueger ! Follow me !
[ SCREAMS ]
Damn it !
Where are you ?
Where are you , Krueger ?
I know you 're here .
automated VOICE : Final 10 seconds .
Nine , eight , seven , six ...
FREDDY : Nancy .
NANCY : I got you now !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ ALARM CLOCK RINGING ]
I 'm crazy after all .
[ FREDDY YELLS ]
[ FREDDY GRuNTING ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
It 's on , Krueger !
Take it down ! Come and get me !
Help ! I 've got him ! Hey , Daddy !
I 've got him trapped ! Help ! Where are you ?
Everything 's gonna be all right ! Everything 's under control !
Get my dad , you asshole !
Daddy !
Come on ! He 's in here !
Don 't let him kill me too !
[ YELLS ]
[ NANCY SCREAMS ]
Come on , Freddy . Can 't you catch me ?
I 'm gonna split you in two .
[ FREDDY YELLS ]
Help ! Daddy , help me , please !
Maybe I better go tell the lieutenant .
FREDDY : I 'll kill you slow .
Now , where are you ?
Hey !
No ! No , no ! No !
[ FREDDY SCREAMING ]
[ NANCY SCREAMS ]
Daddy , I did it ! Please hurry !
Daddy !
Where are you ?
THOMPSON : Parker , I need some help here !
PARKER : Okay , you guys . Come on , let 's go . Let 's go . Al , Jim , get over here .
- Nancy ! NANCY : Daddy !
- Daddy ! THOMPSON : Get you out .
NANCY : Open the door ! PARKER : Watch yourself , lieutenant .
I got it .
NANCY : Dad , it 's Krueger ! THOMPSON : Get out of the way .
[ NANCY SCREAMING ]
Nancy .
PARKER : This way , guys . Come down here .
COP : What the hell came through here ? PARKER : As if I know .
Oh , my God .
Nancy , what the hell is going on ?
Parker , get up here !
- We got a fire up here too . PARKER : Okay , yeah , we 're on our way up .
THOMPSON : What the hell is going on , Nancy ?
NANCY : He 's after Mother !
[ SCREAMS ]
Daddy ! Watch out ! He 's under there !
[ thunder CRASHING ]
Mother ! Mother , Mother !
Now do you believe me ?
PARKER : They 've got the fires out downstairs .
Everything okay up here ?
I 'm okay .
You go downstairs .
I 'll be there in a minute .
Lieutenant , is everything all right ?
THOMPSON : I don 't know . I don 't know .
I know you 're there , Freddy .
FREDDY : You think you was gonna get away from me ?
I know you too well now , Freddy .
Now you die .
It 's too late , Krueger .
I know the secret now .
This is just a dream . You 're not alive .
This whole thing is just a dream .
I want my mother and friends again .
You what ?
I take back every bit of energy I gave you .
You 're nothing .
You 're shit .
[ FREDDY SCREAMS ]
God .
It 's bright .
It 's gonna burn off soon , or it wouldn 't be so bright .
- Feeling better ? - Oh , I feel like a million bucks .
They say you 've bottomed out when you can 't remember the night before .
You know , baby , I 'm gonna stop drinking . I just don 't feel like it anymore .
Did I keep you awake last night ?
You look a little bit peaked .
No . I guess I just slept heavy .
Okay . I 'll see you .
See you .
TINA : Stop it . MARGE : Hi , everybody .
GLEN : You believe this fog ? - Oh , I believe anything is possible .
ROD : Bye . TINA : Looking good , girl .
GLEN : Hey ! - What happened ?
ROD : What 's going on ?
- Hey . Hey , I 'm not doing this . NANCY : Glen ! Let us out !
- I 'm not doing this . - What 's going on with the window ?
No , Mother !
- Mother ! Mother ! Mother ! ROD : What 's going on ?
GIRLS [ CHANTING ] : One , two Freddy 's coming for you
[ SCREAMING ]
Three , four Better lock your door
Five , six Grab your crucifix
Seven , eight Gonna stay up late
Nine , 10 Never sleep again
[ ENGLISH SDH ]